NARRATOR: Two decades had passed since the creation of both species.
两大种族出现已过了二十年
The war had begun.
战争早已展开
Viktor increased his army, creating a legion of vampires
维多壮大他的军队 创造吸血鬼军团
to protect them from the very first clan of werewolves:
来保护他们 免受第一个狼族的攻击
A vicious and infectious breed unable to take human form ever again.
这个邪恶又有传染性的物种 永远无法转换成人形
Until he was born.
直到他出世
Lucian.
路西安
And although every fiber of Viktor's soul warned him to slay this child,
虽然维多身上的每个细胞 都警告他要处决这个孩子
he did not.
但他没有
Over the years, this child grew.
过了许多年，这孩子长大了
He possessed a strength and focus that the ones before him did not.
他拥有先前那个物种所没有的 力量和专注力
What do you think, Sonja?
你觉得呢，桑雅？
Shall we make more?
我们们该多制造一些吗？
Of him?
制造他？
Like him.
像他一样的东西
Lucian will always be the first of the breed,
路西安永远都会是狼人族的始祖
the first of the Lycans.
第一个狼人
Viktor would use Lucian's infectious blood to his benefit,
维多利用路西安具传染性的血
taking advantage of the child's thirst,
利用这孩子的饥渴
pitting it against him as he was forced to feed on humans,
逼迫他啃食人类
Viktor's slaves.
也就是维多的奴隶
MAN 1: Get in there. MAN 2: In there.
- 进去！- 进里面去
Instead, he created a new race of immortals:
他创造了一个新的不死种族
Lycans.
狼人族
Werewolf, but also human.
是狼也是人
Unlike the others, this new breed could be harnessed,
和其他种族不同 这个新种族可以被铐上颈轭
enslaved to guard them in the daylight hours of their masters.
役使他们在白昼守护他们的主人
Or so Viktor thought
或者维多是这么盘算的
so very long ago.
那是在很久以前
The nobles are upset, my lord.
贵族们很不高兴，大人
William's pestilence has not been checked.
威廉的传染病并未停止
Werewolves have killed their slaves. VIKTOR: Humans upset.
- 狼人们杀了他们的奴隶- 人类很沮丧
Tannis, please take a note of what pain that brings me.
谭尼斯，记下我对这点感到很难过
Yet their lost slaves means our lost silver.
他们没了奴隶代表我们没了银子
Enough. Have I not increased our holdings tenfold
够了！ 马可士和埃米莉去冬眠后
since Marcus and Amelia took their sleep?
我不是增加了十倍的收入？
We will deal with the wolves as we always have.
我们会照常对付狼族
MAN 1: Come on! MAN 2: Come on, quickly!
- 快点！- 快啊！
MAN 3: Fire!
射击！
MAN 4: Close that breach.
降下大门门
Have you nothing better to do, blacksmith,
铁匠，你除了把玩武器之外
than play with weapons of war?
没别的事好做了吗？
At least make yourself useful.
做点有用的事吧
A little gratitude, Sonja, to the one who saved your life.
对救命恩人要心存感谢，桑雅
I needed no saving.
我并不需要人救
Tell me, Lucian.
告诉我，路西安
Does it burden your heart to kill your own kind?
杀你的同类会令你心情沉重吗？
Not at all. They're mindless beasts, my lord.
不会，它们是无知的野兽，主人
No brethren of mine. VIKTOR: Really?
- 不是我的伙伴- 真的？
Father.
父亲
You are a credit to your race. Do you know how to remain so?
你是你们族人的荣耀 你知道该怎么保持这点吗？
Keep your eyes on the ground.
眼光别离开地面
Get rid of that.
把那个处理掉
You were sorely missed at council.
议会很关切你的缺席
There are other demands on my time, as you know.
我还有其他事要忙
I see. I hope you enjoyed your little moonlit ride.
是啊，希望你享受月夜的奔驰
SONJA: I was out patrolling.
我是去巡逻
You were disobeying. I told you to stay within these walls.
你根本是抗命 我说过要你待在城墙之内
You risk too much for a father to ignore.
爸爸不能再任你挺而走险了
You will leave the wolves to the Death Dealers.
把狼族留给禁卫军处理
And why, Father, is my risk any greater than theirs?
为什么？我冒的险又不比他们 大
They are not my daughters,
他们不是我女儿
and they are not council members. You are.
他们也不是议会成员，你是
And one day, you will become an elder, your birthright.
有一天，你会继承我 成为长老
Sonja, you are well thought of at council,
桑雅，议会很体谅你
but that is a precarious thing.
不过那么做太危险了
They grow tired of your games and your absences.
他们开始厌烦你的游戏和缺席
The dangers of the forest are no greater than those of the council chamber.
森林里潜藏的危险 并不比议会厅里多
You will learn the dance of politics, to be ruthless and cunning.
你要学会舞弄政治 学会冷酷又狡猾
And above all, you will be loyal to your family.
更重要的是，你要对家族忠诚
To me.
对我忠诚
After all, without the loyalty between us,
毕竟，我们之间若没有忠诚
we are no better than the beasts at our door.
就与门口那些野兽无异
MAN: Put your back into it.
给我继续做
Pick that up.
捡起来
Move it, you scum.
快点，废物
More spin.
多一点
Get up.
起来
Lycan.
狼人族
No rest, dog.
不准休息，快工作！
Enough.
够了
You dare raise your hand to me?
你竟敢反抗我？
I said, that's enough. So says the master's dog, hm?
- 我说够了- 当主子的狗就能大声啦？
You will not always be his favorite, and when you fall,
你不会永远受他宠爱的 当你失宠时
I will be there.
我必会在场观看
Let us hope so.
等着瞧吧
What are you looking at? Get back to work now!
你们看什么？ 马上回去工作！
Get back to work!
回去工作！
The matter before the council is simple.
议会眼前的议题很简单
We are under attack.
我们正遭受攻击
Six times in half as many weeks,
这些日子以来有许多次
William's kind have reached our very walls.
狼族都攻到了我们墙边
What mayhem would follow ifjust one of them got through?
若被攻破将会出现何等混乱？
Your fear, Coloman, is misplaced.
你的恐惧，克洛曼，是无谓的
Are we not protected by an army of immortals?
不是有支不死大军护卫我们们吗？
COLOMAN: Superbly, my lord.
是啊，大人
However, the nobles are not, and as I have pointed out,
然而贵族们并不觉得…
they are the grass on which we graze.
我说过，他们是我们的财富来源
If we cannot protect our humans, it makes us look weak.
我们若无法保护人类 就表示我们的衰弱
And how would you project strength?
那么你们要如何展现力量？
As our Death Dealers patrol the night,
夜里由我们的禁军巡逻
so our daylight guards can patrol the day.
白天则由我们的白昼门卫巡逻
Lycans patrol outside the walls?
狼人族去城外巡逻？
Have you lost your mind?
你是不是疯了？
They are born of beasts,
他们是野兽的后代
and the savagery of this despicable fact cannot be bred away.
这可鄙的事实不会消失的
I think your fear of this idea is misplaced.
我想你对这想法的惧怕是无谓的
We can create a privileged class of Lycans.
我们可以创造一群特级的狼人族
Greater rations, finer quarters, and put them under the hand of one we trust.
提供更好的粮食、宿舍 让他们接受我们信赖的人来统领
Perhaps your pet, Lucian.
也许就是你的宠物，路西安
The one who saved your daughter's life today.
今天救了你女儿一命的那个家伙
In fact, I think we should hear her thoughts on this matter.
事实上，我想该听听她的想法
She seems to have been needed elsewhere.
她似乎在忙别的事
Find her.
去找她
I will take your suggestion under advisement.
我会将你的建议 纳入考虑
Thank you, my lord.
谢谢您，大人
It would be gratifying to be able to reassure the nobles
在明天贵族们抵达时 能向他们重申我们对他们的关切
when they arrive tomorrow that we have their interests at heart.
将会是件令人高兴的事
MAN 1: Move it! MAN 2: Move it!
- 快点！- 动作快！
MAN 3: Go on, slowpoke.
继续，懒猪
Over there. There.
去哪里
MAN 2: Move it! MAN 1: Don't go slow. Keep going.
- 快啊！- 别慢下来，继续走
Move it along!
动作快！
My lady?
小姐？
SONJA: Is it true what you told my father,
那是真的吗？你跟我父亲说…
that you feel nothing when you kill them?
你杀它们的时候毫无感觉
They're just animals,
它们只是野兽
incapable of thought or feeling,
完全不会思考或感受
so why should I feel anything for them?
我为什么要对它们有感觉？
Sonja, if I were to leave from here, would you come with me?
桑雅，如果我要离开这里 你愿意跟我走吗？
Leave?
离开？
Do not say that.
别提那个字眼
Do not even think it. They would hunt you down
连想都别想 他们会猎杀你
and they would mark you like all the others. Not if I could remove this.
-把你当野兽-若我能拿掉这个就不一定了
Look.
你看
I made it.
我做的
This will be my freedom.
这是我的自由
Lucian, promise me you won't use it.
路西安，答应我你不会用它
Please. Is that your answer, then?
- 拜托- 那么这就是你的答案了？
You will not come.
你不会跟我走
So you want me to stay here for you?
你要我为你留下？
Like this, like an animal? Lucian.
- 像这样？像动物一样？- 路西安
Vampire and Lycan, we are both children of Corvinus,
吸血鬼和狼人 我们们都是柯文诺斯的子孙
yet my family are slaves.
然而我的族人却是奴隶
I will use this key,
我会用这把钥匙
and I will leave this place,
我也会离开此地
but I can never be without you now.
不过没有你我不会走
VIKTOR: Any news of my daughter? She's most defiant.
- 有我女儿的消息吗？- 她很叛逆
She refuses to see me.
她拒绝见我
Will not answer her door. Why are the young so blind?
- 也不肯应门- 年轻人怎么都这么盲目？
She risks her seat on the council, and for what?
她会丧失议会席次，是为了什么？
I cannot imagine.
我无法想像
We must prepare, my lord.
我们得准备了，大人
Human nobles are on their way.
人类贵族已经上路了
It's sharp. No wolf will stand before it.
它很锋利，必能劈死恶狼
Ready the horses.
备马
Let someone else go.
让别人去吧
Why? Last night, after I left you...
- 为什么？- 昨晚，我和你分手之后…
In case it had escaped your notice, blacksmith,
你可能没注意到，铁匠
I am quite capable of looking after myself.
我很有能力照顾自己
And besides,
还有
you can watch over me from the wall.
你可以从城墙上看着我
MAN: Get your back to the rear.
回去后面
Lady Sonja, your father has ordered you to stay behind.
桑雅小姐，您父亲下令要您留下
I intend to see our guests safely through the gate.
我想亲自护送我们的客人
Gate master. This is not a request.
- 守门人- 这不是请求
Your father is ruler of the coven.
您父亲是我们的领袖
So he keeps reminding me.
他也一直提醒我这一点
MAN: Get back!
回去！
Careful, blacksmith,
注意点，铁匠
lest your eyes betray your secret.
别让你的眼神泄露秘密
Steady. Steady.
稳住
Shut it, my child. Shut it.
关上窗，孩子
Form up!
准备迎击！
No.
不
Get your men out there now!
快让你的手下出去
Down, boy. Your leash is too tight.
冷静点，你太激动了
Step away. There's too many of them.
- 站开！- 它们太多了
They'll be massacred.
这会是一场屠杀
Stop him!
阻止他！
MAN: Ride out. Ride out.
骑出去…
Easy.
小心
Dimitri.
狄米崔！
SONJA: Lucian!
路西安！
LUCIAN: Sonja!
桑雅！
Lucian, no.
路西安，不！
No, stop!
不！住手！
He did it to save me.
他是为了救我
Am I not master of this house?
我不是主人了吗？
You know you are forbidden to remove your shackle.
你知道你不准拿掉颈轭的
Yes.
是的
Yet you break my law after I gave you your life.
我赐你新生，你却抗命
Your days of plush living are over, slave.
你舒适的生活结束了，奴隶
Father, leave him be.
父亲，放了他
I told you... Hold your tongue!
- 我说过…- 给我住嘴
You have defied me for the last time.
这是你最后一次违抗我的命令
Get her out of here.
把她带走
Burn the bodies.
烧了尸体
Burn them all.
全都烧掉
VIKTOR: For removing the collar,
因为拿掉颈轭…
30 lashes.
三十鞭
You have stung me, Lycan, with your betrayal.
你的背叛令我难过，狼人
You were like a son to me.
你原本就像是我的儿子一样
I gave you your life.
我给了你生命
You gave me chains.
你却给我枷锁
I would have thought, after all these years, you would have known
我早该想到 经过这些年，我早该学会
you cannot have one without the other.
你毕竟得跟你的同类在一起
Do it.
动手吧
I told you I'd be there when you fell.
我说过你失宠时我必会在场
What? Stop this.
- 怎么？- 住手吧
He is one of our protectors. They are but beasts themselves.
- 他是我们的门卫之一- 他们只是野兽
This could stir up the others. Let them stir. Do you fear them?
- 这可能会激怒其他狼人- 那就让他们去，你怕他们？
Believe me, it will be worse if we do not punish them.
相信我，不惩罚只会更糟
Do you see now, Coloman? You would trust them
你以为在城外能信任他们？
outside the walls? We cannot even trust them inside.
他们们连在城内都信不过了
By my count, that's 21.
照我计算，那是第二十一鞭
Continue.
继续
MAN 1: Oh, what a terrible sound.
好可怕的声音
MAN 2: Bloody stink.
臭死了
Stay away from him, or they'll punish you too.
离他远点 不然他们也会惩罚你
Your concern for Lucian was most touching.
你对路西安的关心真令人感动
A slave.
一个奴隶
He had just saved my life.
他刚刚救了我一命
Was it not you who told me to show a little gratitude?
你之前不是叫我要心存感激？
And yourself?
那你自己呢？
Have you no gratitude for the one who saved your daughter's life?
你不感谢救你女儿一命的人？
I am awash with it.
我感激涕零
That he lives shows the breadth of my magnanimity.
他能活命显示我的宽容大量
Were it any other circumstances,
换做别的情况
I would have had him fed in pieces to his own kind.
我早把他扔去 给他自己的族人分食
But his punishment is now over.
不过他的惩罚现在已经结束了
He will be freed. Freed?
- 你会释放他吧？ - 释放？
Your judgment is clouded, Sonja.
你的判断有点迟钝
We do not keep order with sentiment.
我们不是用情感来保持秩序的
Lucian was forbidden to remove his collar, and yet he did so,
路西安拿掉他不准拿掉的颈轭
for however fine a reason.
不论理由有多好
He will remain in prison,
他都得留在牢里
a cautionary tale.
用以告诫他人
Janosh and the other nobles will soon arrive.
琼纳和其他贵族即将抵达
Your presence is expected.
你的出席是必要的
I saw what you did out there.
我看到你的身手
Very brave
很勇猛
for a human.
对一个人类而言
Have you come across them before?
你之前遭遇过它们吗？
Only in stories.
完全没有
Were you not afraid of them?
你不怕它们？
Yes,
怕
but I wanted to live.
不过我想活命
Are you afraid of me?
你怕我吗？
Yes. Well, do not be.
- 怕- 不用怕
I will not bite...
我不咬人
much.
不大咬啦
You are like them? No.
- 你跟它们一样？- 不
A Lycan, yes, but not like them.
我是狼人，但跟它们不一样
Those you fought with tonight were animals, the spawn of William.
你今晚对抗的是野兽 是威廉的子孙
Purebloods, if you will. No trace of human left.
血统纯正 完全没有人类的基因
Savage, mindless beasts.
野蛮、无知的野兽
As it has been told. But I saw you.
- 和传说一样- 不过我看到你
They obeyed you.
它们听你的
Yes.
是的
Yes, they did.
对，没错
SONJA: Hey.
嘿
Oh, you should not be here. I had to.
- 你不该来此- 我必须来
My love, I'm sorry.
我的爱，对不起
Your back. No, no, I'm all right.
- 你的背- 我没事
This is my fault. If I had not gone out...
是我的错，要是我没出去…
Then you would not be who you are.
那你就不是你了
This is not your fault.
这不是你的错
I cannot remain here. I have to leave this place.
我不能留在这里，我得离开
My father will be watching you now more than ever.
我父亲现在会更严加监控你
What about your Death Dealers, are there none that you can trust?
禁军呢？里面没你的亲信？
Unfortunately, their loyalty to my father is greater than their loyalty to me.
他们们对我父亲比对我忠心
Tannis.
谭尼斯
Tannis cannot be trusted. No, Tannis, he knows about us.
- 不能相信他- 不，他知道我们的事
How? I have no idea.
- 怎么会？- 我不知道，不过
But if he still has not told your father, then that must mean he wants something.
若他还没告诉你父亲，那就有鬼
Sonja, find out what it is.
去查他在打什么算盘
Bring them in.
带他们进来
Janosh.
琼纳
Do you not own the largest silver mine in these lands?
你不是拥有最大的银矿吗？
It has been overrun, my lord.
已经都荒废了，大人
Our workers infected,
工人都受到感染
turned to beasts.
变成野兽
VIKTOR: Most unfortunate,
真不幸
and costly.
牺牲真大
I think half the rights to your mine
我想你矿场一半的权益…
should cover the expense of our assistance.
应该能偿付我们协助的费用吧
What assistance?
你们的协助？
We have all seen the fires on the way here.
我们在来的路上都看到火焰
We have learned of the deaths of Baron Covasha and his family.
也知道巴伦和他家人的死讯
The wolves are at your door as well.
狼群也攻到了你们城下
So why should I pay tribute
你们连自保都有问题
when you cannot so much as protect your own house?
我为什么要进贡给你们？
You have all but bled me dry already.
你已经把我榨乾了
We have all heard the stories.
我们都听说了
Look into his eyes. They are true.
看他的眼睛！是真的！
This place is cursed.
这里受到诅咒
They are no more human
他们是入侵…
than the devils that invade our lands.
我们土地的恶魔
If devils you call us, rest assured, better the devil you know.
放心，跟你认识的恶魔交手 胜过跟不认识的打交道
Unhand me. Certainly.
- 放开我- 当然
Would anyone else like to be heard?
还有谁有话要说？
Toss it here. Bring food to these filthy mongrels.
把食物送给这些肮脏的狗
Here you go. Eat it up like dogs.
- 来了- 跟狗一样舔吧
MAN: Like dogs.
跟狗一样
We are not animals.
我们不是野兽
Is this what you want, to be their entertainment, their playthings?
难道你们想当他们的玩具？
Their pets.
当他们的宠物？
Cowering beneath the whip
蜷曲在鞭子之下
and then fighting amongst ourselves.
却在彼此之间争斗
Is this what you want?
这就是你们想要的？
I have lived by their rules my entire life.
我一辈子听从他们的指挥
I've protected them,
我保卫他们
envied them.
羡慕他们
And for what?
结果呢？
To be treated like an animal.
结果却被当成野兽对待
We are not animals!
我们不是野兽
We do have a choice.
我们有选择
We can choose to be more than this.
我们们可以选择比这更好的
We can be slaves
我们可以是奴隶
or we can be Lycans!
我们也可以是狼人
VIKTOR: Morning is upon us, my child.
晨光已现，我的孩子
It's time we left this wretched night behind.
我们该将不幸的夜置诸脑后
Gladly. There are some difficult decisions ahead.
- 我很乐意- 眼前有一些困难的决策
I would like your help with one of them. Of course, Father.
- 我希望你帮我解决其中一个- 当然，父亲
With Lucian gone,
失去了路西安
we must promote another Lycan in his place.
我们得拔擢另一个狼人取代他
Gone?
失去？
Coloman thinks he will stir the others.
克洛曼认为他会煽动其他人
We must remove him.
我们必须除掉他
That will be difficult.
这很困难
He has been with us so long.
他跟我们这么久了
Perhaps Gyorg.
也许用吉尔吧
Or Thrasos.
或塞拉索
They would be
他们都很…
trustworthy.
值得信赖
Excellent suggestions.
很好的建议
I will consider them strongly.
我会仔细考虑
You, my child, are the most precious thing in my heart.
你，我的孩子 是我心中最珍贵的宝贝
What have you told my father?
你跟我父亲说了什么？
What have you told him? Nothing.
- 你说了什么？- 什么都没说
Why? Why what?
- 为什么？- 什么为什么？
Why have you told him nothing?
为什么没说？
Would your father welcome the man who brought him news
你的父亲 会很高兴有人告诉他
that his beloved daughter was consorting
他心爱女儿的交往对象…
with a Lycan?
是狼人吗？
He isn't well known for his gratitude.
他是知名的冷酷无情
And I am not yet in a position to use this for my benefit.
我还不想利用这个消息 替自己谋福利
What sort of benefit?
什么样的福利？
There are 12 council seats.
议会的议员有十二席
And we don't die often.
我们又不常死人
Sadly, no.
真可惜，是啊
So, what if I gave up my seat at council?
要是我放弃我在议会的席次
Simply left it to you?
直接留给你呢？
Why would you do that?
你为什么要那么做？
Can you keep a secret?
你能保守秘密吗？
I will need something in return.
我需要一些回报
Two minutes.
两分钟
Any longer is too risky.
再久就会有危险
I'm sorry. There was no other way.
对不起，我没有别的办法
So Tannis?
谭尼斯？
You were right. He will help us in exchange for a seat on the council.
你说的对，他要议会的席位
Your father knows nothing? I'm sure of it.
- 而你父亲毫不知情？- 我很确定
Sonja, this can work. Lucian, it has to.
- 桑雅，这样行得通- 必须如此
I think some of the others will come with me.
我想有些狼人会跟我走
Sabas and Xristo, the human Raze. My love...
- 萨巴斯、瑞思托、雷兹- 我的爱…
I'm certain I can... Lucian, there is no time.
- 我肯定可以…- 路西安，没时间了
My father will have you killed tomorrow, after the humans are turned.
我父亲明天等人类离开 就会处决你
You must leave at sunrise.
你必须在天亮时离开
And you? The important thing is you stay alive.
- 你呢？- 重要的是你保住性命
The best chance you have is when Viktor and the Death Dealers sleep.
维多和禁军入睡时 是你的好机会
I will be safely at my father's side when you go.
你走之后，我在父亲身边很安全
TANNIS: Hurry.
快点
If this plan works, I'll meet you in three days' time, after the sun sets.
计划若成功，三天后日落时见
There's a clearing by the river. I'll meet you there.
河边有个空地，我在哪里等你
And if it doesn't? I will meet you at the clearing.
- 不成功呢？- 我会在空地等你
MAN: Face the wall.
靠墙站好！
Get out. MAN: You animals.
- 出来- 你们这些野兽
You. Get back.
你！马上回去！
Be brave, human.
勇敢点，人类
TANNIS: You know what your problem is?
你知道你有什么问题吗？
You don't understand the natural order of things.
你不明白大自然的法则
Things change.
凡事都会变
Be ready when they do.
那你可要准备好了
Consider it a parting gift.
把这当成临别的礼物吧
Wait.
等等！
Do you not realize this is a gift I am giving you?
你不明白这是我给你的礼物？
RAZE: It's a curse.
这是诅咒！
What have they done to us? You'll find out soon enough.
- 它们？对我们做了什么- 你很快就会知道的
They turned us into... Like you?
他们们把我们变成…你们
Yes.
对
Why?
为什么？
He wants to use you for his own protection.
他要利用你来保护他
I will die first.
我会先死
Well, that may not happen.
那可能不会发生
The time has come.
时候到了
At sunrise, I leave this place.
天亮时，我会离开此地
Anyone willing to take the risk may follow me.
愿意冒险的人可以跟我走
There is a new life waiting beyond these walls, my friend,
墙外有新的生活等着我们
and you can be a part of it, one of us,
你可以成为我们的一部分
or stay and serve them.
或是留下来侍奉他们
MAN: The guards are coming.
警卫来了
New dogs today. Let's see how they look.
今天有新狗，看看他们的长相
You've come too late.
你来太晚了
He's already gone.
他已经走了
Are you with me?
你们要跟我走吗？
LUCIAN: Sabas, Xristo, free the others. The rest of you with me.
萨巴斯、瑞思托，释放其他人 其他的跟我走
Freedom is yours.
你们自由了
Move!
快走！
This way.
往这边！
Down here.
下面！
All right, move. Run, run, run.
快走！跑！跑！
Keep moving.
继续跑！
MAN: Fire.
发射！
Raze.
雷兹！
There is nothing you can do.
你无能为力了
I will come back. I promise you.
我会回来的！我保证！
No!
不！
My lord.
大人
My lord, Lucian is escaping.
大人，路西安逃走了
Forest, go. Go!
往森林去！快去！
My lord.
大人！
MAN 1: Move here. Move it.
快点！
You, get in there. MAN 2: Move.
- 你！进去！- 快点！
MAN 3: Are all these accounted for? MAN 4: Each and every one.
- 就这些？没漏掉任何一个？- 是的
VIKTOR: Tannis.
谭尼斯？
Come on. Move.
快点！
TANNIS: Yes, my lord?
是的，大人
Where is the key I gave you for this?
我给你的钥匙在那里？
I locked it in the armory myself. How, then, is it open?
- 我亲自把它锁在军械库的- 那么它是怎么开的？
I have no idea.
我不知道
I think I have.
我想我知道
Kill him. No.
- 杀了他！- 不！
Please.
求求你
Check the armory.
去看军械库
There has to be an explanation.
一定有一个解释的
Show me.
带我去看
I've never been outside the walls. LUCIAN: Well, enjoy it while you can, Xristo.
- 我从没出过城- 趁你可以享受时享受吧
Because soon enough we're gonna have to fight our way back in.
因为我们很快就得打回去了
We did not all make it out, and I will not leave our brothers to rot back there.
我们没全逃出来 我不会丢下弟兄…
We humiliated Viktor. It is they who will pay the cost.
维多受辱，会拿他们出气
But we were lucky to make it out alive.
不过我们很幸运能活着逃出来
And there's but a handful of us. We have no weapons.
我们们人数不多，又没武器
True, for now.
目前是如此
The noble who brought you here, can you lead us back to his estate?
你能带我们去贵族的领地吗？
Yes. Good. Come on. Come on.
- 可以- 好，走吧
It has to be here.
一定在这里
I put it here.
我放在这里
Here.
在这里
He must have made another one.
他一定还有另一把
I never doubted you.
我从未怀疑过你
Now, I have no wish to remove one shackle from around your necks
现在我不想卸除你们的颈轭之后
only to replace it with one of my own.
却铐上我对你们的箝制
You have a choice.
你们有选择
You can run and hide
逃跑或躲藏
or you can stay and fight.
或是留下来奋战
Any man who fights with me shall have his freedom
与我并肩作战者，享有自由
and, if he wishes it,
如果他想要的话…
immortality.
还有不死之身
MAN 1: Pick up your weapons.
捡起你的武器
Together we're strong.
我们团结才能壮大
There are other estates to the west of here.
西边有其他的贵族领地
I want you to go there.
我要你去哪里
See how many will join us.
看有多少人要加入我们
I will meet you back here in two days' time.
我们两天后在此碰头
MAN 2: Put it over there. MAN 3: Over here.
- 放在哪里- 哪里
SONJA: Father.
父亲
Did I startle you? I'm sorry.
我吓到你了？对不起
No.
没有
You did not.
你没有
It occurs to me
我突然想到
that I have been thoughtless.
我一直都太粗心大意了
So deep have I been in my own anguish at Lucian's betrayal,
我太沉浸于路西安背叛的痛苦
I gave no thought
却完全没考虑到…
to your feelings.
你的感受
My feelings?
我的感受？
They worm their way into our lives,
他们们融入我们的生活之中
and we forget the travesty of their birth.
我们却忘了他们可笑的出世
I myself had tenderness towards Lucian.
我自己对路西安充满慈悲
He could have been anything.
他可以成就大事
A Death Dealer, perhaps.
也许还可以当禁军
Yes.
是啊
Perhaps.
也许吧
But he was not as we are,
不过他毕竟与我们不同
was he?
对吧？
Did you help him escape?
你是否帮助他逃亡？
Help him?
帮助他？
Of course not.
当然没有
Are you lying to me?
你在欺骗我？
There are many things that I have done against your will,
我是做过很多违抗你的事
but he is a Lycan.
可是他是狼人
I'm sorry, my dear,
对不起，乖女儿
but you leave me no choice.
你让我别无选择
Father, please...
父亲，求求你
I wanted to believe your lies though I knew it could not be true.
我原本想相信你的谎言 虽然我知道那不是真的
Not my own daughter. How could you?
可是我的亲生女儿，你怎么能？
Father,
父亲
I love him.
我爱他
You have betrayed me!
你背叛了我
To be with an animal!
跟野兽在一起
I loved you more than anything!
我爱你胜过一切
She does not leave this room!
不准她离开房间
No. You're under orders to wait.
不行，我们受命要等待
Here.
这里
This rate, we'll have enough men by the end of the week.
照这速度，到周末人手就够了
Has there been any sign of Sonja? Nothing.
- 有桑雅的消息吗？- 没有
She should have been here by now.
她应该早就到了
With respect, Lucian, I do not see the wisdom in waiting for her.
路西安，等待她并不明智
She's not one of us.
她不是我们的人
Have you forgotten she is the one who set us free?
你忘了是她释放我们的吗？
But she is a vampire.
可是她是吸血鬼
If she has deceived you, she could lead them here.
若她骗你，她会带他们来此
Death Dealers will undoubtedly be on the hunt,
禁军绝对会大举出击
and they will eventually find us, but not by her doing.
他们终究会找到我们 不过不会是她告的密
I trust Sonja with my life, and as long as I'm in command, so shall you.
我相信桑雅，你们也该如此
Told you not to say anything.
就跟你说什么都别讲吧
Lucian has sacked two estates in Brashov, my lord, and made off
路西安掠夺了布莱霍夫的两个庄园
with the contents of their armories. The slaves have joined his ranks.
还偷走了他们的军械 而奴隶们加入了他的队伍
COLOMAN: Freedom is as much a disease as William's pestilence.
自由就像威廉的瘟疫一样蔓延
You need to bring your pet back. Thank you, Coloman.
- 你得把你的宠物弄回来- 谢谢，克洛曼
The obvious escaped me.
我显然疏忽了
I do not need to lift a finger. Lucian will return of his own free will.
我不用动一根手指头 路西安会自己回来的
I have something he wants.
我有他要的东西
My lady.
我的爱
Luka. What is it? Where is she? Sonja has been arrested.
- 露卡，怎么回事？她人呢？- 桑雅被逮捕了
He knows about the two of you.
他知道你们的事了
He will kill her.
他会杀了她
I thought you should know.
我想你该知道
Nothing yet, my lord.
还没有动静，大人
RAZE: It is a trap. You know that. I will not let her die alone.
- 这是陷阱，你很清楚- 我不会让她孤独死去
They followed you here, Lucian. If you go, we will lose them.
它们追随你来，你走 它们也会走
Let me tell you a secret, my friend. They thought they followed me.
让我告诉你 它们以为它们是追随我而来
What they truly followed was the idea of being free. That's what brought them here.
但它们真正追随的是自由 那才是吸引它们来的原因
Now, you can hold them together until I get back, and lead them if I do not.
你可以带领它们等我回来 我若没回来，则由你领导它们
Are you all right? Yes.
- 你没事吧？- 没事
But Lucian, you were free.
可是路西安，你已经自由了
Not without you.
没有你就不算是
We have to go now.
我们得马上走
My lord,
大人
your daughter has escaped.
您女儿逃走了
Of course she has.
她当然会逃
This way.
往这边！
That one. Yes, sir.
- 那一个- 是，大人
Now.
就是现在！
How dare you raise your hand to me?
你竟敢对抗我？
I do not want this. I am your father.
- 我不想这样- 我是你父亲
Do you think you can defeat me? I don't want to defeat you.
- 你以为你能打败我吗？- 我不想打败你
Killing me won't save your precious Lycan.
杀了我并不能救你的宝贝狼人
Please call off your men, for the sake of your grandchild.
为了你的孙儿，撤回你的人
A miracle, Father.
这是奇迹，父亲
A union of the bloodlines.
两条血脉的融和
I curse the day your mother gave her life to bring you into this world.
我诅咒你母亲生下你而死的那天
That thing inside you
你体内的东西
is a monstrosity.
是个怪物
LUCIAN: Sonja!
桑雅！
VIKTOR: This is over.
都结束了
Remove him.
带走他
Do you understand what you have done?
你明白你干了什么好事吗？
This night was not about you. It was about him.
今晚不是要逮你，而是要逮他
I could have given Lucian to the council.
我原可将路西安交给议会
They need never have known of your indiscretion, but after this,
他们不需要知道你鲁莽的行为 不过经过这一切
never.
别想了
LUCIAN: No!
不！
If I had not left, none of this would have happened.
要是我没走，这一切都不会发生
Then you would not be who you are.
那么你也不会是你了
You were right.
你说的对
No one should live a life like this.
没有人该过这种生活
Others are free because of you.
其他人因为你而自由了
Things are forever changed because of what you have done.
因为你的作为，一切已彻底改变
But I have failed you. No.
- 不过我令你失望了- 不
Lucian, my love,
路西安，我的爱
you have not failed me.
你没有令我失望
The choices I made have led me here.
是我做的决定让我来到这里
Not you.
不是你
You said yourself there are risks that you were willing to take for me,
你说过你愿为我承受危险
as was I for you.
为了你我也一样
For us.
为了我们
MAN: Open the door.
开门！
No. MAN: Get up.
- 不- 起来！
No. No. MAN: Come on. Come on.
- 不，不- 快啊
LUCIAN: No. I'll kill you.
不，我会杀了你！
All of you!
你们全部！
The accused has committed high treason against the coven.
被告的罪名是谋逆
She has consorted with animals. She has abetted in their escape.
她与野兽往来 她帮助他们逃亡
I have saved this coven many times over.
我拯救过我族许多次
You have killed your own kind.
你也杀害过自己的同胞
And you've commingled bloodlines,
你还混杂血脉
resulting in the thing germinating within you.
在你体内培育出那玩意儿
Your past glory does not excuse your present guilt,
你往日的荣耀无法为你今日脱罪
nor does your station as a council member.
你身为议会成员的身份也一样
The punishment for these crimes is death.
这些罪行的惩罚是死刑
How vote you?
请表决
Aye.
赞成
Aye. Aye.
- 赞成- 赞成
She's your daughter.
她是你女儿
Aye.
赞成
COLOMAN: Take her to the chamber.
带她去死刑室
No, you... You cannot do this.
不，你们不能这么做
MAN: My lady, come with us.
跟我们来
Come quietly, please. Viktor.
- 请保持静默- 维多！
Viktor. No!
维多！不！
No.
不！
Lucian.
路西安
No, Sonja.
不，桑雅
Don't. Just look at me.
不要，看着我
Keep your eyes on me, Sonja.
眼睛看着我，桑雅
Look at me!
看着我！
I love you.
我爱你
As I love you.
我也爱你
Your face will not be here when this is over, will it?
等一切结束，你就不在了，是吧？
Goodbye, my love.
再见了，我的爱
No.
不
Sonja!
桑雅！
Fetch my knives. Yes, my lord.
- 去拿我的刀- 是，大人
My lord.
大人
Go. Go. Quickly. Go.
快去…
Now go free the others. Go!
去放了其他人，快去
Follow me.
跟我来
Do you want your revenge? MEN: Yeah.
- 你们想复仇吗？- 想！
It is out there. Now go.
就在外面，去吧
We have greater concerns than your precious scrolls.
我们有比卷轴更重要的东西
Go to the elders, now!
快去找长老！快！
Kill the dogs!
杀了这些狗奴才
Viktor.
维多
You defiled my daughter.
你玷污了我女儿
I loved her! You killed her!
- 我爱她- 你害死了她
I should have crushed you under my heel the day you were born.
你出生那天我就该踩碎你的头颅
Yes, you should have...
是啊，你是应该
but you didn't.
可是你没有
MAN: Lucian!
路西安
It is finished.
都结束了
No.
不
This is just the beginning.
一切才刚开始
MAN: But let me tell you a little something about your beloved dark father.
让我告诉你 你所深爱的黑暗之父
He's the one who killed your family. Not the Lycans.
他才是害死你家人的人 不是狼人
But when he got to you,
不过当他看到你
he just couldn't bear the thought of draining you dry.
他就是无法承受 想吸乾你的血的想法
You, who reminded him so much of his precious Sonja,
你让他想起他的宝贝桑雅
the daughter he condemned to death.
他亲自判刑处死的女儿